Hi there, I'm Charles Martin and I'm the lecturer
for COMP2300/6300 computer organization and
program execution here at the ANU.
This course is about learning how
your computer actually works. We'll look at the
different parts of a CPU, how they fit together,
and how the high level programs that you
might write in other courses get turned into
instructions that the CPU can actually execute.
I just want to welcome everyone to this course
whether you're here on ANU
campus or whether you can't be
with us this semester you're all very welcome.
Most of the content for COMP2300/6300 is already
online on our website and you can check it out.
Now one of the really exciting things about
this course is that everyone will get one
of these... this is a microbit and it's a
tiny computer which fits in your pocket. It's
got a little CPU which you can use in your labs
and assignments to understand how the CPU in
your laptop or desktop computer actually works.
A lot of this course looks like this,
you'll be writing programs in assembly
that means you'll be directly controlling
what the CPU on your micro bit is doing.
We'll be looking at how high-level
programming concepts from C,
Java or Python might get transformed into
assembly instructions that your computer can run.
You'll learn some fundamentals
about operating systems and networks
and how they relate to your computer's hardware.
Finally, a theme of this course is that the
assignments are about making expressive
and creative programs for your microbit.
The microbit has buttons, it has LED lights,
it has a speaker, and you can use it to create
a sound and light show or an interactive toy.
This course is a lot of fun, and I think you're
really going to enjoy it.
See you in week one!